<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-04T14:00:02-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">AnnL</title><subtitle>γνῶθι σεαυτόν - &quot;know thyself&quot;</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/09/02/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2020-09-02T20:50:04-07:00</published><updated>2020-09-02T20:50:04-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/09/02/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/09/02/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR&lt;/code&gt; is a four-digit number, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MONTH&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DAY&lt;/code&gt; are both two-digit numbers, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MARKUP&lt;/code&gt; is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Deepwater Horizon disaster</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/case/study/2020/02/28/deepwater.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Deepwater Horizon disaster" /><published>2020-02-28T19:33:56-08:00</published><updated>2020-02-28T19:33:56-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/case/study/2020/02/28/deepwater</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/case/study/2020/02/28/deepwater.html">&lt;h2&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Deepwater Horizon oil spill is the largest marine oil spill in history. The explosion on the rig killed 11 crewmen. The Horizon sank and caused millions of barrels of oil spewed unchecked into the ocean, which is one of the largest environmental disasters in American history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;b&gt;Education&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a drill operator, a high school diploma is necessary. However, the structure of the whole drill is complicated. Even Mike Williams, the Chief Electronics Technician, didn’t distinguish the danger of the breakdown of annular(the rubber gasket).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is essential people on the manager level have a basic understanding of the system and mechanism. Mandatory training or classes about the structure of the oil rig is suggested for the manager level or above. Only if they know what’s vital for safety, they will be able to make the right decision. At the end of the day, they are the ones on-site and if anything goes wrong, they are the ones risking their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the operator, I recommend induction will also be conducted at the operational and theoretical level even they are having experience in other oil rigs before. Oil rig practice might vary depends on companies or sites. 
Someone argues that the worker neglect the rubber gasket cause care about the progress of the oil drilling but I was thinking what if the supervisor was not educated to recognize the risk behind a chunk of rubber. I believe people will do everything to bring the issues up to higher up if they realise how much a missing seal will damage the whole system and demanded a replacement for the seal before they operate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies should also provide subsidy for employees’ wanting to upskill themselves as long as they promise to come back and work for them after they finish their related degrees or courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bug Bounty/reward or whistleblower(reporting) system(external and internal)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a couple of reasons why no one does anything and resulted in 6 out of 7 safety system(eg. Blow-out preventer failed to seal, inadequate cement, Failing separator, Pressure test misinterpreted, blind shear ram failed to plug the oil, dead man switch) failed to stop the closing down the rig and oil spilling, hence the ignition, explosions, and loss of power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspections on the oil rig were supposed to be done at least once per month and apparently &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/bp-rig-missed-16-inspections-before-explosion/&quot;&gt;BP missing 16 inspections&lt;/a&gt; before the explosion. Qualifications of the inspector are under question. I would argue that if they hire people who have more experienced and professional to inspect will be more appropriated. A reward system may encourage them to take it more seriously rather than ticking all the boxes without properly checking all the components or at least what’s essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Mike Williams, the operator like him on site noticed that some parts of the safety system fell apart. There should be a centralized report system for safety concerns. It happens sometimes that the supervisor has a different point of view and it’s easy to let it go. If we have a proper report system, the supervisor will have to take it seriously since they are the ones in charge of the part of the system. They should have a second thought before they make a decision and they are the ones to blame if anything happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The person who reports the problem will often see as a whistleblower. They might get blacklisted or complaint if they report the problem on-site. This practice encourages the culture of fear of speaking up as it is affecting their mobility or their careers. If we reward this practice and do it anonymously, people will find it more beneficial to file a report and know that there is no consequences for doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;b&gt;Distributed power or authority&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the deepwater horizon disaster, BP is not the only company that is working in the rig. The oil drilling process had involving multiple companies. There is breakdown of management communications between BP, Halliburton Co(contractor), and Transocean Ltd(rig operator). BP was the one blamed for favoring the time and cost savings due to financial pressures since the delay of the operation causing them. They were not doing a good job on coordinating with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hurleywrite.com/Blog/84835/The-BP-Oil-Spill-in-the-Gulf-of-Mexico-Largely-Due-to-Communication-Failures&quot;&gt;Hurley Write’s article&lt;/a&gt;, the exchange of information is lacking between companies. For example, BP implemented adjustments to the rig and its safety procedures without an understanding of how they would affect the rig and its workers. Halliburton failed to share information on the cement seals being produced. It led to inaccurate examine assess risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a grey area for the management that none of the companies are claiming responsibility. The unclear of duties results in shred responsibility after the incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;b&gt;More frequent crew rotation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employees on the rig site are high-risk workers. It took time for workers to adjust to the working environment. It is not a common practice for individuals to work 12-hour shifts every day, however, it is mandatory for crews to maintain 24-7 operation, which affects their life cycle by the long and irregular working hour. In the deepwater horizon, the crew routine is 21 days offshore and 12 working hours a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These workers have a higher chance to perform poorly due to fatigue and attributed to mistakes in the rig. There is a need to examine the workload and working hours from time to time. The operators should have rest breaks or nap time during the working hour. Regular medical checkups conducted by the companies will be a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;b&gt;Regulation on standards&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government should propose that monitoring offshore drilling properly. Oil companies should be required to report accidents to the government which forced to replace the dysfunctional components of the rig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can stop BP for pushing the progress of the oil rig by restraining the rate of penetration or other procedures for drilling. And the bottom of the drill will not split open and mud, the drilling fluid, will not be stuck in the bottom of the rig. One of the safety systems would have worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Interesting reading&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PR response after deepwater horizon
https://www.psandman.com/col/deepwater4.html&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Case" /><category term="Study" /><summary type="html">Background The Deepwater Horizon oil spill is the largest marine oil spill in history. The explosion on the rig killed 11 crewmen. The Horizon sank and caused millions of barrels of oil spewed unchecked into the ocean, which is one of the largest environmental disasters in American history.</summary></entry></feed>